<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>course on Shubham Gupta</title>
    <link>https://ishub.github.io/tags/course/</link>
    <description>Recent content in course on Shubham Gupta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ishub.github.io/tags/course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Airbnb Property Pricing Prediction</title>
      <link>https://ishub.github.io/project/airbnb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ishub.github.io/project/airbnb/</guid>
      <description>Paper selected to be presented at Southeast Decision Science Institute</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics as a Service</title>
      <link>https://ishub.github.io/project/aas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ishub.github.io/project/aas/</guid>
      <description>Integrated OpenStack with Hadoop through data processing and thereby managed Hadoop clusters within the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the scenes of a hit track</title>
      <link>https://ishub.github.io/project/spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ishub.github.io/project/spotify/</guid>
      <description>In 2017, revenues from recorded music in the United States were estimated at a retail value of $8.7 billion, this market includes streaming services, live shows, record labels, artists, song writing and video streaming, which relies heavily on a single factor, the success of a song.Record Labels and artists release thousands of songs across various genres to get a few hit songs to get return on their investment. Considering the size of this market, there still lies ambiguity in what makes a song popular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craiglist Spam Ad Filter</title>
      <link>https://ishub.github.io/project/craiglist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ishub.github.io/project/craiglist/</guid>
      <description>Millions of ads are posted every single day on Craigslist worldwide to a large extent anonymously. Millions of housing listings are posted in a month. It is difficult to check the listings for the people looking for a new house. As per trends 6% of housing ads are spams. However, they can’t run all around the world policing and prosecuting people. This project intends to solve the house hunt problem by sending the updates of new listings as per the selection criteria of the user by filtering spam in housing listings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crude Oil Price Prediction Modeling</title>
      <link>https://ishub.github.io/project/crudeoilprice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ishub.github.io/project/crudeoilprice/</guid>
      <description>Analyzed the existing studies of prediction models for crude oil prices and developed a software system for real-time crude price analysis and prediction. The data was sent to Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) and processed using MapReduce programs in Python. The data visualization was done using Python Graphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack the talk</title>
      <link>https://ishub.github.io/project/handwrittenrecog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ishub.github.io/project/handwrittenrecog/</guid>
      <description>Emotion detection in human speech</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing Superheroes</title>
      <link>https://ishub.github.io/project/marvel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ishub.github.io/project/marvel/</guid>
      <description>The study involves evaluating the marketing strategies and efforts by Marvel Studios</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Restaurant Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ishub.github.io/project/nyrestaurant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ishub.github.io/project/nyrestaurant/</guid>
      <description>Analysing the NYC restaurant inspection scores</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Intrusive User Interaction Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://ishub.github.io/project/openlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ishub.github.io/project/openlab/</guid>
      <description>Publication: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.33583&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/DOI/10.5281/zenodo.33583.svg&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequence Analysis approach to improve product forecasts</title>
      <link>https://ishub.github.io/project/autoparts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:01:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ishub.github.io/project/autoparts/</guid>
      <description>Worked with the leading auto part seller in the US, to improve sales forecast by implementing a sequence analysis approach with time-series data to improve the accuracy of the model.
This study investigates a novel application of sequence analysis to forecast new product demand, which is a modified version of the approach that has been used in the bioinformatics field for protein sequencing. For retailers, the problem of forecasting demand for products which have never existed previously is challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>